前情提要
他是总督察
He's a Chief Inspector.
我猜他是要对共产主义分子下手
I reckon it's Communists he's after.
那个警察是不会来找我们麻烦的  对吧
So this copper's going to leave us alone, right?
什么情况
What the fuck?!
我希望你把这当做我对你的自我介绍
I want you to see this as me introducing myself to you.
他说是丘吉尔阁下派他来伯明翰的
He said Mr. Churchill sent him to Birmingham.
跟盗窃案有关
Something about a robbery.
汤玛斯  你经营赌马公司  但你不傻
Thomas, you are a bookmaker, you're not a fool...
你敢把枪卖给任何一个能发挥其用武之地的人
You sell those guns to anyone who has use for them,
你就死定了
you will hang.
我只是个多嘴的共产主义穷小子
I am just a poor communist frog with a big mouth.
我跟你在一起
I'm with you
因为你是这里唯一不怕他们的男人
cos you're the only man round here not scared of them.
弗莱迪  你和我之间唯一的区别
The only difference between you and me, Freddie,
就是有时我的马还有可能赢
is that sometimes my horses stand a chance of winning.
汤米
Tommy!
你现在还操纵比赛了吗
You fixing races now?
我是来应聘酒吧女侍的
I'm here about the job as barmaid.
你打入进去了吗
Are you in position?
是的  先生
I am, sir.
第一季   『人人影视英剧社倾情奉献』   第二集
我以为你是要带我们去集市呢
I thought you said we were going to the fair.
先谈生意要紧  下车吧
We have business first. Come on.
放机灵点
Bring your wits.
-谈什么生意  -那是李氏家族的人
- What business? - That's the Lee family.
汤米
Tommy!
约翰尼·道格斯
Johnny Dogs.
汤米  你最近怎么样
Tommy, how the hell are you?
出城呼吸下新鲜空气  人清爽多了
All the better for getting the city smoke out of me lungs.
我以为你现在已经看不上我们了
I thought you became a bit too grand for us.
我最近太忙了
I've been busy.
我现在跟着李氏家族做事
I'm riding with the Lee family now.
我听说了
I heard.
换做是我  我宁可跟猪住在一起
Myself, I'd rather live among pigs.
行了  汤米  别引发争端
Come on, Tommy. No disputing.
自你从法国回来后第一次来集市吗
So, your first fair since France...?
你知道法国什么事啊
What do you know about France,
你个怕打仗的吉普赛小杂种
you war-shy Gypsy bastard?
就是这匹马吧
So this is the horse.
就是那辆车吧
And that's the car.
等一下
Hang on a minute.
你不会想要拿家庭用车换那匹该死的马吧
You are not swapping the family car for a bloody horse.
当然不是交换
Of course we're not swapping it.
那简直是疯了
That would be mad.
我们要用抛双币来决定
We're going to play two-up.
浴   血
黑   帮
第一季   『人人影视英剧社倾情奉献』   第二集
给你
Here you are.
我就知道  就知道
I knew it. I knew it.
汤米  你个该死的白痴
Tommy, you bloody idiot.
闭嘴  亚瑟  我赢了
Shut up, Arthur, I won.
我答应过约翰尼如果他输了
I promised Johnny I'd let him
就让他开车出去兜一圈
have a spin in the car if he lost.
那就好
All right.
你们这帮姓李的小子们是在笑话我大哥吗
Are you Lee boys laughing at my brother?
是吗
Are you?
汤米
Tommy...
-汤米  -我问你们话呢
- Tommy. - I asked you a question!
汤米  好了  他们就是图个乐而已
Tommy, come on, it's just the craic...
带你的家人离开这  好好逛集市去吧
Get your family out of here and go and enjoy yourselves at the fair
别让他们挑起争端
before they start a war.
快点  走啊  他们出生于上流家庭
他们的祖父曾是称霸一方的王
没错  但他妈妈就是个吉普赛婊子
Yeah, but his mother was a Didicoy whore.
我们要赶在他们昨晚喝的啤酒化成尿
We will take them before last night's beer
在他们心中的邪恶苏醒前  将他们一举抓获
turns to piss and wakes the devils up.
我们不要放过任何地方
We will leave no stone unturned.
每把枪  每颗子弹
Every gun, every bullet
都要带回来做进一步检查
will be brought to me for inspection.
现在
Now...
各就各位吧
take your positions.
不要打我  放开我
Don't hit me! Get off me!
弗莱迪
Freddie!
你确定你的兄弟们都去集市了吗
You're sure your brothers are at the fair?
他们才不会敲门呢
If it was them they wouldn't knock.
索恩先生
Mr. Thorne...
什么事
What is it?
警察正在围捕共产主义分子
The police are rounding up the communists.
快点  艾达
Come on, Ada,
如果警察找到我  我们就完蛋了
if the cops find me we are screwed.
妈的
Fuck...
-弗莱迪·索恩  快开门  -艾达
- Freddie Thorne, open up! - Ada...
你得跳下来  艾达  我会接住你
You have to jump, Ada. I'll catch you.
快跳
Come on.
看这个
Look at this.
一张铁元素补充剂的处方
A prescription for iron tablets...
患者是该死的艾达·谢尔比
for Ada fucking Shelby.
多诺万太太  我需要你帮忙
Mrs. Donovan, I need that favour.
-速度进屋  -不是我要进去  是她
- Come in and be quick. - I'm not coming in. She is.
我的老天  是谢尔比家的女孩
Holy Jesus, it's the Shelby girl.
别说你看到过她跟我在一起  多诺万太太
You have not seen her with me, Mrs. Donovan.
请她喝杯茶
Give her a cup of tea and
等警察走了再让她离开
let her stay until the police have gone.
她是那帮剃刀党恶魔的妹妹
She's the sister of those Peaky Blinder devils...
但她却是位天使
And yet she is an angel.
快点  艾达
Come on, Ada.
你要怎么办  弗莱迪
What are you going to do, Freddie?
我吗  我得出城避避风头
Me? I'm going to have to leave town for a bit.
真正的绅士会摘下他的帽子
A gentleman would take off his hat...
熄灭他的烟斗
and put out his pipe.
我发现你们这帮特派员只有在
I see you Specials only dare to come here
那帮小子们去集市时  才敢来这里
when you know the boys are away at the fair.
你是说你的外甥们吗
You mean your nephews...
天天挥舞着他们的枪跟剃刀
with their guns and their razors?
你是在为他们点蜡烛吗
Is it them you're lighting candles for?
不是
No.
我是为那些早逝的加里森青年们点的
I am lighting candles for the boys from the Garrison
他们牺牲在了法国
who lost their lives in France.
那里有份名单
There's a list there.
抬起头来看
Look...
我听说你没去过法国  坎贝尔总督察
I hear you didn't make it to France, Inspector Campbell.
你听说过我
You've heard of me.
我也听说过你
I've heard of you.
你是在找圣杯吗
Is it the Holy Grail you're looking for...?
事实上
As a matter of fact...
我就是在找圣杯呢
it is the Holy Grail I'm looking for.
那是些宝贝  但却被偷了
Something precious. Something stolen.
或许你明白我指的是什么
Perhaps you know what I'm talking about.
真抱歉  您这样把我抵在墙上
Sorry, I misunderstood your intention
我误会您的意思了
when you pushed me to the wall.
把这儿给我翻个底朝天
Turn the place upside down.
亚瑟·谢尔比说你们愿意帮忙
Arthur Shelby said you people would help us.
我们都不知道你丢了什么  要怎么帮忙找
If we don't know what you've lost, how can we help you find it?
但后来我意识到我是找错了人
But I've found out subsequently that I was speaking to the wrong man.
下次  我要找老大问话
Next time I want to talk to the boss.
利奇茶馆  周五十点
The Lickey Tea Rooms. Friday. Ten o'clock.
我说的老大  是指汤玛斯
And when I say the boss, I mean Thomas.
走吧
Come on.
真他妈的
The scum of the Earth...
这儿他妈是出了什么事了
Now what the bloody hell's been going on here?
天呐
Jesus Christ.
警察跟大家说这是亚瑟被捕时允许了的
The coppers told everyone Arthur had agreed to it when he was arrested.
他们说剃刀党
They said the Peaky Blinders
故意去集市躲避着  好让他们动手
had cleared out to the fair to let them do it.
我可没跟那警察说
I never said nothing to that copper
他们可以来砸人家的房子
about smashing up bloody houses...
行了  他们去搜查了哪些酒吧
All right... which pubs did they do?
火枪酒吧  铁链酒吧和侯爵酒吧
The Guns, the Chain, the Marquis.
都是交了保护费的
All the ones that pay you to protect them.
就是没去加里森
The only one they didn't touch was the Garrison.
好让人们相信这事是我们主使的
Make sure people think we were in on it.
那个警察很精明
He's smart, this copper.
快点行动啊
So, go on.
把酒喝了  然后出去
Drink your beers, get out.
你们得让大家知道你们仍旧是这里管事的
You'd better show people you're still the cocks of the walk.
给酒吧的房东拿些钱
Hand out some cash to the landlords of the pubs.
雇几个老兵去把那儿修好
Pay some veterans to fix the places up.
伙计  把包给我
Oi, Nipper. Give us the bag.
你呢  汤米
So, what about you, Tommy?
我得把马牵去查理那儿
I have to go to Charlie's to stable the horse.
它似乎生了脚疮
She looked foot-sore in the box.
让他们看见你
Let them see your faces.
我们都知道他们到底在找什么
So we both know what they were looking for.
你不读报纸吗
You don't read the papers.
只读关于赌马的
Racing papers.
那我跟你说说情况吧
So let me tell you the odds.
我敢以三赔一的赔率打赌会发生革命
I reckon it's three to one there'll be a revolution.
我可不会拿这种事打赌
I wouldn't bet on that.
那个警察也赌会这样
That copper's betting on it.
他不找回那些枪是不会罢休的
He's not going to let it rest till he gets those guns back.
他找你谈过了吗  波莉
Did he talk to you, Pol?
在教堂里
In the church.
他还去找艾达了吗
Did he try to find our Ada?
她当时在睡觉
She was sleeping.
她在哪睡的  波莉
Where was she sleeping, Pol?
我以为你不在乎女人的事呢
I thought you didn't care for women's business.
他知道你才是老大
He knows you're the boss.
他要见你
He wants to meet you.
你会去跟他谈谈吗
Will you talk to him?
不
No...
处于守势的人不能谈判
you don't parley when you're on the back foot.
我们得先回击一拳
We'll strike a blow back first.
芬恩  你干什么呢
Finn, lad? What are you doing?
我们要点火了
We're having a fire.
两先令换国王的画像
Two bob for your picture of the King.
什么
What?
拿去清水巷
Bring it to Watery Lane.
-芬恩  好伙计  -斯卡德  你好啊
- All right, Finn, lad. - All right, Scud.
我们要把入口拦住
We are blocking the entrance, mate.
来  继续往前走  来吧
Come on, keep making your way through. Come on.
来吧  先生们
Come on, gentlemen.
快点
Now come on...
丢进去吧  伙计们
Chuck them on, boys.
我希望你明白自己在干什么
Well, I hope to God you know what you're doing.
我是《伯明翰晚报》的记者
I'm a reporter with the Birmingham Evening Despatch.
我接到电话赶来的
I had a phone call.
是个叫汤玛斯·谢尔比的人
Someone called Thomas Shelby.
跟我来
Come with me.
来  借过
Come on, folks, give us a bit of room.
汤米
Tommy.
-大家让一让  -您是谢尔比先生
- Move back for us, please, folks. - You're Mr Shelby?
-大家退后一点  -正是
- All the way back, please. - I am.
你说我不用担心安全
You said I would be protected.
你绝对安全
You're protected.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我要你写点东西
There are some things I want you to write down.
首先
Now, first of all...
并不是这里的人民不效忠国王
it's not that people round here are disloyal to the King.
恰恰相反
It's the opposite.
是这样  我们不想让敬爱的国王看到
You see, we don't want our beloved King looking down
我们遭受的不公待遇
and seeing the things that are being done to us.
所以我们摘下了他的画像
So we are taking down his pictures.
但你为什么要烧掉呢
But why are you burning them?
我们为国王九死一生
We went through hell for our King.
走过战火  把这都写下来
Walked through the flames of war. Write all this down...
如今却在自己家门口受到攻击
And now we're being attacked in our own homes.
那些从贝尔法斯特来的新警察
These new coppers over from Belfast,
他们闯进我们家
breaking into our homes
骚扰我们的女人
and interfering with our women.
我们认为国王肯定不忍看到这样的事情
We don't think our King would want to see that happening.
所以我们点火警示世人
So, we're lighting fires to raise the alarm.
我能问您  您是什么身份吗
May I ask you, in what capacity do you speak?
没什么身份
No capacity.
我只是一介草民
I am an ordinary man.
我在索姆河一役中赢得了英勇勋章
I won Gallantry Medal at the Somme.
我要你在你的报纸上刊登这里发生的事
I want you to write in your paper what's going on here.
走吧  去写
Go on, go.
请进
Come in.
那个
Here, eh...
有电话找您  长官  是伦敦打来的
there's a telephone call for you, sir, on the London line.
是吗  这都要午夜了
There is? It's almost midnight.
是温斯顿·丘吉尔先生  长官
It's Mr Winston Churchill, sir.
您好  阁下
Yes, sir?
坎贝尔督察
Inspector Campbell?
我听说你城里有人聚众焚烧
I hear there has been a bonfire in your city.
是有报告称9点左右清水巷有几人在烧东西
There was a small fire reported around nine o'clock on Watery Lane.
不过您完全无需为这种小事担心  阁下
But it was certainly nothing to trouble you about, sir.
但恐怕我已经在担心了
Ah, but I'm afraid it has troubled me.
半小时前  我收到一封
Half an hour ago I received a wire communication
来自《伯明翰晚报》的编辑的电报
from the editor of the Birmingham Evening Despatch.
他的一名记者受邀参加了焚烧聚会
It seems one of his reporters was invited to the fire
发现他们在焚烧国王的画像
and discovered that they were burning pictures of the King.
国王的吗
Of the King?
任何可能导致国王陛下难堪的报道
Any newspaper report which may cause embarrassment to His Majesty
都是首要大事
is always referred first
也是内政部的例行公事
and as a matter of routine to the Home Office.
我会立刻赶过去  逮捕涉案人员
I will go down there immediately and arrest those involved.
不  你绝对不能抓人
No, you most certainly will not make arrests.
你抓了人  就还得审讯
If there are arrests there will be trials,
一旦审讯  就会有更多报社报道
if there are trials there will be more newspaper reports,
而这必然会提到
which will necessarily mention
焚烧国王画像的事情
the burning of the King's likeness.
我把你派到伯明翰有一个特殊原因
I put you in Birmingham for one very specific reason.
让你寻找失窃枪支一事到底有没有进展
Are you any nearer to finding those stolen guns?
我们取得了一些进展
We are making steady progress...
我们要的是结果
We need results.
-晚安  坎贝尔先生  -阁下
- Good night, Mr Campbell. - Sir...
我能问问  那篇报道
Could I at least ask, does this report
有提到某些参与者的名字吗
name any of those involved?
提到了一个叫汤玛斯·谢尔比的
It names a Mr Thomas Shelby.
报道提到他是一位战争英雄
The report mentions he is a war hero.
你终于出现了
Good of you to join us.
-你这一天都上哪儿去了  -躺床上啊
- Where have you been all day? - In bed.
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep.
然后又睡得醒不来
Then I couldn't wake up.
后来我很冷  后来我不得不起床撒尿
Then I was cold and then I had to go for a wee.
我和一头熊同坐一条船
Then I was with this bear on a boat,
但那只是个梦
but that was a dream.
再后来我就饿了
Then I was hungry.
你为什么要看报纸
Why are you reading the paper?
我为什么不能看
Why wouldn't I be?
我从没看你读过报纸
I've never seen you read the paper.
我只看过你拿来点火
I've only ever seen you light fires with them.
伯明翰轻武器公司罢工了
The BSA are on strike.
矿工罢工了
The miners are on strike.
爱尔兰共和军一天内杀了我们10个孩子
IRA are killing our boys ten a day.
怎么了
What?
站起来
Stand up.
为什么
Why?
站起来就是了
Just stand up.
侧过身去
Side on.
天啊  你在干什么
Hoi! What are you doing?
艾达
Ada...
月经比正常晚来多久了
how late are you?
一周
One week.
五周了
Five weeks.
算上周末就七周了  我以为是因为缺铁
Seven if you count weekends. I think it's a lack of iron.
我拿了点药片
I got some tablets.
但不管用吗
But they didn't work?
没用
No.
你可以穿上衣服了  亲爱的
You can get dressed now, love.
那我到底有没有怀孕
So, am I or not?
赶紧走  艾达
Keep bloody walking, Ada.
被人看到我们在这儿  他们肯定会知道的
If anybody sees us here they'll know.
我不会打掉孩子的  波莉阿姨
I'm not getting rid of it, Aunt Pol.
回家后我们再商量这事儿
Just come home and we'll talk about it.
你别抓着我  不然我就叫了  我发誓
You get off me or I'll scream out, I swear.
好  如果你想在大街上谈  那就开始吧
All right, if you want to do this on the street, let's do it.
谁的孩子
Whose is it?
如果我告诉你  你就会告诉他们
If I tell you, you'll tell them
他们会把他碎尸万段的
and they'll cut him to pieces.
如果他娶了你  他们就不会那么做
Not if he marries you they won't.
他会娶你吗
Will he marry you?
我不知道  我不知道他上哪儿去了
I don't know. I don't know where he is.
-老天啊  艾达  -他跑了  但他说会回来的
- Jesus Christ, Ada. - He's gone away, but he said he'd come back.
是啊  男人都说自己会回来的
Yeah, but they all say they'll come back.
他不是那种人  他是个好人  他保证过的
He's not like that. He's a good man. He promised.
他会回来的  波莉阿姨  我知道他会的
He will come back, Aunt Pol, I know he will.
给我安上西班牙马鞍  科利
Get me down a Spanish saddle, Curly.
是  汤姆  西班牙马鞍
Yes, Tom, a Spanish saddle.
它可真漂亮  汤姆  美人儿啊  汤姆
He's a beauty, Tom. Yeah, yeah, a beauty, Tom.
你这匹马真不赖啊  汤姆斯
A fine beast you got there, Thomas.
但真的值得你为此跟李家闹翻吗
But is he worth falling out with the Lee family over?
我只是带个信
Just passing it on...
宣战  整个李氏家族
a declaration of war - the whole Lee clan.
先是枪  现在又是这个
The guns and now this.
千万不要在任何场合提枪
The guns are not spoken of.
明白吗
Right?
汤米
Tommy...
注意点你跟我说话的态度
you mind how you speak to me.
原谅我  叔叔
Forgive me, Uncle.
汤姆斯·谢尔比要跟全世界作对  是吗
It's Thomas Shelby against the whole bloody world, right?
放轻松
Easy...
放松  放松
Easy, easy.
冷静点  小子
Easy, boy.
我们以前在法国时常说
In France we used to say...
In France we used to say
只是音乐厅的乐队来了
it's just the music hall band turning up.
是长号和大号的声音  不过如此
It's just trombones and tubas, that's all.
噪音罢了
It's just noise.
噪音罢了  只是点噪音而已
It's just noise. Hey. It's just noise.
你得学会适应
You get used to it.
噪音而已  好孩子  乖孩子
It's just noise. Good boy. Good boy.
你脚掌疼是吗  小子
You have some pain there, boy, hey?
我很抱歉  谢尔比先生
I'm so sorry, Mr Shelby.
顺便说一下  我叫格蕾丝
I'm Grace, by the way.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
它叫什么名字
What's his name?
它还没名字呢
He doesn't have a name.
可怜的孩子  该给它取个名字
Poor boy deserves a name.
你有事要跟我说吗
You have something to say to me?
那天晚上你到酒吧的时候  我在唱歌
The other night you came into the pub and I was singing...
你说这里不允许唱歌
You said singing wasn't allowed.
我希望每周能有一个晚上允许唱歌
I'd like there to be one night a week when there's singing.
我觉得那对大家都好
I think it would be good for everyone...
每周六晚上
Saturday nights.
哈里不敢问你  所以
Harry was too afraid to ask you, so...
但你不怕
But you're not.
我也怕
I am.
但我热爱唱歌
But I love to sing.
你的口气听上去像是
You sound like one of those rich girls
那些从都柏林来参加赛马会的富家小姐
who comes over from Dublin for the races.
你喜欢马吗
Do you like horses?
你想挣点外快吗
How do you fancy earning some extra money?
怎么挣
Doing what?
找件漂亮的礼服
Dig out a nice dress.
我带你去赛马会
I want to take you to the races.
摩纳根小子  一赔二
Monaghan Boy two to one.
在比赛开始前下注吧
Get your bets in now before he goes evens.
我们的赔率有点小变动  约翰
We've got a couple of changes coming in, John.
"石轮渡"跌到八了
Rock Ferry down to eight.
-给你  -谢了  伙计
- That's for you. - Thanks, mate.
赶快下注吧
Get your bets in now.
一赔二十
20-1.
-好了  拿到双胞胎那去  -知道了
- There you go, take that to the twins, yeah? - Yeah.
-赔率跌到十了  -没错
- Down to tens. - That's right.
加倍吗
Doubles?
好的朋友  我买摩纳根小子
OK, friend, Monaghan Boy.
要全部倒出来吗  老兄
You want to push out, mate,
比赛就快开始了
cos it's going to go evens soon.
很好  找你35磅
Good one. Change of 35 pounds...
我告诉过你  抱歉  谢尔比先生
I've told you... Sorry, Mr Shelby.
快点走
Go on!
谢尔比先生  最近好吗
All right, Mr Shelby, how's it going?
-弗兰克  腿怎么样了  -还行
- Hello, Frank, how's the leg? - Not bad.
很高兴见到你  孩子
Nice to see you, son.
早上好  查理
Morning, Charlie.
斯卡德伯特  情形如何
All right, Scudboat, how are we looking?
-挺好的  汤米  -真是好东西
- Looking good, Tommy. - Grand stuff.
汤米  人们都跑来押摩纳根小子
Tommy, they are all here for Monaghan Boy.
我就爱听这个  约翰尼小子
That's what I like to hear, Johnny Boy.
波莉阿姨想见你
And Aunt Pol wants to see you.
告诉我那个男人是谁  艾达
Tell me the man's name, Ada.
鲁道夫·瓦伦蒂诺[影星]
Rudolph Valentino.
出去  全都出去
Get out! All of you!
快点  现在就走
Go on! Now!
我说  把那个狗日的名字告诉我
I said, tell me his fucking name.
该死的弗莱迪·索恩
Freddie fucking Thorne!
没错
Yeah.
你的同窗好友
Your best mate since school!
那个在法国救你一命的男人
The man who saved your life in France!
去吧
So go on!
去吧  砍死他
Go on, cut him!
把他绞碎抛尸去吧
Cut him up and chuck him in the cut.
喂  我也是谢尔比家的人
Oi! I'm a Shelby too, you know.
给我他妈的继续放电影
Put my fucking film back on!
摩纳根小子终于输了
So Monaghan Boy finally lost.
第三次就是最不幸的
Third time unlucky.
我们把整个城市的钱都席卷来了
We took money from all over the city.
是啊  但你得把附近街坊的钱送回去
Yeah, but you'll pay it back to people round here.
买回你的声望
Buy your popularity back.
已经做了
Already done.
我把你教得很好啊
I taught you well.
没得到比利·肯波的允许你就操控赛马
And you fixed this race without the permission of Billy Kimber.
很显然  我把你教得还不够好
Obviously, I didn't teach you well enough.
第一条规矩  不要挑战远超自己实力的人
Rule one, you don't punch above your weight.
比利·肯波我们是可以对付的
Billy Kimber is there for the taking...
谁说的  汤米和他手下的散兵游勇吗
Says who? Says Tommy and his parliament of one.
我掌管了5年的家族事业
I ran this business for five years...
是啊  我出国打仗去了  记住
Yeah, while I was away fighting, remember,
我在战场上可是学到一些东西的  比如
where I learnt some things, such as
敌弱我攻
you strike when your enemy is weak.
我以为你过来是为了谈家事呢
I thought you came here to talk family business.
我来处理
I'll deal with it.
-你一心忙于掌控全世界  -波莉
- You're too busy taking over the world... - Polly...
如果是关于艾达的事  我需要知道
If it's about Ada, I need to know.
艾达让你把这封信交给弗莱迪
Ada wants you to give Freddie this letter.
她想告诉弗莱迪她怀孕了
She wants Freddie to know she's having his baby.
他需要一个机会来做正确的事
He deserves an opportunity to do the right thing.
我觉得我们该给他们一个机会
I say we give them a chance.
作为一个爱情之路坎坷痛苦的女人
For a woman who's had a hard life with men,
你仍然充满着浪漫情怀  是吧
you're still full of romance, eh?
你觉得弗莱迪看上我们艾达哪点了
What do you think Freddie sees in our Ada?
-那是弗莱迪的事  -不
- That's Freddie's business... - No.
不  我来告诉你答案
No. I'll tell you what he sees.
他看上的是机枪  来福枪  军火
He sees machine guns, and rifles, and ammunition,
和什么狗屁的光荣革命
and some glorious revolution.
你究竟不喜欢弗莱迪哪点
What is it you really don't like about Freddie?
她跟着亡命徒是不会幸福的
She'll have no life with a man on the run.
如果你看不明白这一点
If you can't see that,
你就很难看清一切的事
you can't see much.
该死的  他们在法国究竟对你做了什么
Damn them for what they did to you in France.
告诉艾达  弗莱迪去美国了
Tell Ada Freddie went to America.
或者俄罗斯也行
Or Russia.
波莉  让艾达一个人把孩子生下来
Polly, it would do no good for Ada
对她没有任何好处
to bring a baby into the world alone.
波莉  听我说
Pol, listen.
事实上  你之所以没用那个东西打我
The truth is you would have hit me with that thing
就因为你心里很清楚我说的是对的
if it weren't for the fact that you know I'm right.
我好像听到有人敲门
I thought I heard someone knocking.
然后就睡不着了
Couldn't get back to sleep.
你拖得越久
The longer you leave it...
结果就越糟糕
the worse it gets.
相信我
Believe me...
我了解的
I know.
我当年才16岁
I was 16.
不敢告诉任何人
And I didn't dare tell anyone.
波莉  弗莱迪会回来的
Polly, Freddie will come back...
最后是我自己下的手
In the end I did it myself.
我亲手打掉了孩子
I did it to myself...
我差点就死了
and I almost died.
他没回来
And he didn't come back.
他们都不会回来的  他们干嘛要回来
They don't. Why should they?
你知道人们会怎么说
You know the words.
你是个婊子
You're a whore,
孩子是私生子
the baby's a bastard...
但远走高飞的男人却不会受到谴责
but there's no word for the man who doesn't come back.
总有一天
One day...
在你的婚礼上
on your wedding day...
你会手挽着一个好男人
you'll have a good man on your arm...
然后你会说  "波莉
and you'll say, "Polly...
谢谢你当时点醒我"
"Thank you for common sense."
卡迪夫那边有个女人
This woman is in Cardiff.
我们明天坐火车去找她
We'll take the train tomorrow.
事后去城堡玩玩
Go to the castle afterwards for a treat.
我选这个地方是因为这里在你我的辖区之外
I chose this place because it is outside both our jurisdictions.
你想喝茶吗
Do you want tea?
总督察  我应邀前来
Inspector, I responded to your invitation
是为了达成共识
because I want us to understand each other.
我是个生意人
I am a businessman.
我希望我的生意兴隆
I want to make my business successful.
而我希望我的城市和平安宁
And I want my city to run peacefully.
只有城市和平  生意才能兴旺
Well, if the city is peaceful, business can thrive.
这么说我们目标一致
So we are on the same side?
我觉得或许是的
I think perhaps we could be.
但有这种东西存在  我们怎么达成一致
How can we be on the same side when I see things like this?
我的人在一个
My men found this
共产主义分子的卧室里找到的
in the bedroom of a known communist.
上面有你妹妹的名字
It has your sister's name on it.
很明显她和他同床了
It was obvious she had been sleeping in his bed.
你和共产主义分子也同床共梦吗
Are you also in bed with the communists,
谢尔比先生
Mr Shelby?
我不相信他们的白日梦
I do not share their fantasy.
至于我妹妹的事  我已经处理好了
And, as for my sister, I have already dealt with the situation.
我名单上的第一个人就是弗莱迪·索恩
Freddie Thorne is at the very top of my list.
划掉他吧
So cross him off.
他不会再回这个城市了
He won't be returning to the city.
我把他纳入我们的交易条件
I'll make him part of our deal.
什么"交易"
What "Deal"?
你和你的特派员今后不得干涉我的生意
You and your Specials will leave my businesses alone from now on.
不准搜查我们的地盘  不准砸我们的酒吧
No more raids into our territory, no more smashing up pubs
不准查缴我的走私船
and no more lifting my runners.
你必须无视我所有的赌博活动
You will turn a blind eye to all my gambling operations.
而且我准备扩张
Also, I am planning an expansion.
进军赌马生意
Onto the racetracks.
我准备和比利·肯波合作
I intend to do business with Billy Kimber.
他经营着伦敦以外大部分的合法赌马
He runs most of the legal track-side betting outside of London.
他在警队有人
He has policemen on his payroll.
我要你帮我
I want you to put in a word
给格洛斯特郡的总督察传句话
with the Chief Inspector Gloucestershire
让他不要干涉我的行动
that his men should leave me alone when I make my move.
抱歉
Forgive me.
我没带笔
I don't seem to have a pen
记不下这么多要求
to write down this rather long list of demands.
我能得到什么好处
And what do I get in return?
我有你在找的东西
I have what you're looking for.
那些枪在我手上
I have the guns.
什么枪
What guns?
-我不是来玩游戏的  -留步
- I'm not here to play games... - Wait, wait.
25挺刘易斯机枪
25 Lewis machine guns,
50把半自动步枪  10000盒弹药
50 carbines, 10,000 rounds of ammunition -
全装在板条箱里  准备送往利比亚
all in a crate bound for Libya,
从伯明翰轻兵器工厂的打样车间被偷
stolen from the BSA factory proofing bay.
我猜他们派你来伯明翰是为了找回那些枪
I'm guessing they sent you to Birmingham to get those guns back.
枪在我这里
Well, it's me that has them.
我已给信任的人交代过
I have left word with men I trust
如果我因某种原因被警察拘禁
that if I am taken into police custody for whatever reason,
那些枪将被载至利物浦
those guns will be shipped to Liverpool.
然后直接运到贝尔法斯特
From there they will be sent directly to Belfast
卖给爱尔兰共和军
and sold to the Irish Republican Army.
你们在爱尔兰的努力将化为乌有
All your good work in Ireland would be undone.
被偷的枪支上都有序列号和标记
Each stolen weapon is numbered and marked.
如果我卖给爱尔兰共和军  要不了多久
If I sell them to the IRA, it won't be long
丘吉尔先生就会发现
before Mr Churchill finds out.
我想光是焚烧国王画像的事
I imagine you got into enough trouble over
已经让你焦头烂额了吧
the burning of the King's photographs.
那只是小试牛刀
That was just a taster.
如果那些枪抵达了贝尔法斯特
If those guns reach Belfast,
你的警界生涯就结束了
your life in the force is over.
当我达到自己的目的后
When I have achieved what I have set out to achieve,
我会告诉你枪藏在哪
I will let you know where to find the guns.
你会成为英雄  说不定会获得勋章
You'll be a hero. You'll probably get a medal.
我做事公允
I'm a fair man.
这个提议也很公平
It's a fair offer.
成交吗
Do we have a deal?
我需要答案
I need an answer.
现在就要
Right now.
好吧
Very well.
但我不想握手以示成交
But I'd prefer if we don't shake hands on it.
我怎么会和一个
Now why would I shake the hand of a man
没为国家奋战过的人握手呢
who didn't even fight for his country?
格蕾丝
Grace.
我有新信息
I have new information.
汤玛斯·谢尔比现在是
'Thomas Shelby is now the beginning,
你任务的全部内容
the middle' and the end of your mission.
我该做什么
So what shall I do?
我也很心痛  就像一个父亲
It hurts me as much as it would a father
亲手将女儿送进窑子一样  但是
sending his own daughter into a whorehouse but...
不管有多不堪
no matter how repugnant it may be,
你都必须不择手段地接近他  然后
you must do everything you can to get close to him and...
查出枪藏在哪里
find out where the guns are hidden.
当然了  我所说的"不择手段"不包括...
Of course, when I say everything, I don't mean...
你完全低估了我
You underestimate me in every way.
给
Here.
你现在代表国王进行军事行动
'You are now active in a military operation' on behalf of the Crown.
我真希望这个人不是你
I wish to God circumstance hadn't chosen you.
我受训练就是为了这个
It's what I'm trained for.
我上班要晚了
I'm late for my shift.
格蕾丝
Grace...
我心与你同在
my heart is with you.
汤玛斯  汤玛斯
Tom. Tom!
汤玛斯  快来  汤玛斯
Tom, you better come quick. Tom!
科利  怎么回事
Curly, tell me.
这是个诅咒  汤玛斯
It's a curse, Tom.
科利  科利
Curly, Curly,
Curly, Curly.
告诉我
Tell me.
告诉我  科利  你的马出什么事了
Tell me, Curly, what's wrong with your horse?
你在集市上买下它时情况就不好
You bought her at the fair in bad feeling.
李氏家族的人在马蹄掌中埋下了恶毒的种子
The Lees put a bad seed in the hoof,
让一个老妇人下了咒
got an old woman to put a spell...
所以李氏家族那些混蛋诅咒了它
So those Lee bastards cursed her.
不管是什么  他说反正会传染给另外的脚
Whatever it is, he says it's spread to the other feet.
我敢说明天感染就要直达心脏了
It's going to his heart by tomorrow, I'd say.
我见过两次这种诅咒
Seen curses like this twice.
根本没办法撤销  汤姆  做不到
Can't take them back, Tom. No.
我告诉过你  汤米
I told you, Tommy.
流淌着黑色血液的吉普赛人是最惹不起的敌人
Better enemies to have than black-blood Gypsies.
出去
Get out.
出去  科利
Get out, Curly.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们打烊了  谢尔比先生
We're closed, Mr Shelby.
给我一杯酒
Just get me a drink.
我该让您一个人待着吗
Should I leave you alone?
我是来找人作陪的
I came here for company.
哈里去哪儿了
Where's Harry?
他今晚不值班
He took the night off.
他去看电影了
He went to the pictures.
你那匹美丽的宝马怎么样了
How's your beautiful horse?
我刚刚一枪结束了它的生命
I just put a bullet in his head.
它表现太差劲了吗
Was he lame?
它看我的眼神不对
He looked at me the wrong way.
看汤米·谢尔比的眼神不对  下场是很悲惨的
It's not a good idea to look at Tommy Shelby the wrong way.
-真可惜了  -是啊
- What a waste. - Yeah.
确实很可惜
A waste is what it is.
其实  在法国
You know, in France...
在法国时  我已经习惯了见人死亡
In France, I got used to seeing men die.
我却从没习惯见到马死亡
I never got used to seeing horses die.
它们的死相很惨
They die badly.
我按照你的要求找出了一件礼服
I dug out a dress like you asked.
谢谢
Thanks.
你说的是切尔滕纳姆赛马场对吧
Is it Cheltenham you're talking about?
切尔滕纳姆那边的盛会  对吧
Cheltenham's a grand affair, is it not?
国王也会出席的
The King will be there.
乔治国王吗
King George?
不是
No.
是比利·肯波国王
King Billy Kimber...
和他全部的手下
and all his men.
我需要做什么
And what must I do?
给你两英镑  你要对我言听计从
For two pounds, you'll do what I ask you to do.
我要三英镑
I want three.
如果我是要见一个国王  我可不能穿廉价的礼服
If I'm meeting a King, I won't be wearing a cheap dress.
我要求你允许我唱歌
And I asked you to let me sing.
那也是条件之一
That's part of the deal now too.
什么时候成条件了
Since when?
从你差点露出笑容那一刻起
Since you nearly smiled.
周六晚上  气氛轻松
Saturday nights, open and easy.
每个人都可以唱自己想唱的歌
Everyone gets to sing their song
就像我们在都柏林时一样
just like we did in Dublin.
你从没在都柏林工作过
You never worked in Dublin...
别再骗我了
so don't lie to me.
我打听过你说你曾经工作过的酒吧
I asked around about that pub you said you used to work in.
我在那边是有朋友的
I have friends over there.
没人听说过你
No-one has heard of you.
我猜
My guess is...
你曾出身于上层家庭  却不小心怀了孕
you're a girl from a good family who got herself pregnant.
我不喜欢别人知道这种事
It's not something I want known.
独自生下孩子完全毁了你的生活
And bringing a child into the world alone ruined your life.
对吗
Right?
所以我是对的
So I'm right...
波莉是错的
and Polly is wrong.
什么对的
Right about what?
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
似乎对你很重要
It looks like it matters to you.
家事罢了
Family business.
你不会对别人说我的事吧
You won't tell anyone my secret.
你以为我会对任何人说任何事吗
Do you think I tell people things?
你会唱什么歌
So what do you sing?
-你想听什么都可以  -好吧
- Anything you want. - Right.
站到椅子上去
Get up on a chair.
欢乐的歌还是悲伤的歌
Happy or sad?
悲伤的
Sad.
好的
Ok.
但我想提醒你  我会让你心碎的
But I warn you, I'll break your heart.
我心已碎
Already broken.
*在一个叫做贝尔法斯特的小镇*
*In a neat little town they call Belfast*
*我曾在那里做学徒*
*Apprentice to trade I was bound*
*我曾在那美丽的小镇  度过很多快乐时光*
*Many an hour's sweet happiness. Had I spent in that neat little town
*有一天我遭遇不幸*
*A sad misfortune came over me*
*让我远离了那片土地*
*Which caused me to stray from the land
*远离我的朋友和亲人*
*Far away from my friends and relations*
*被黑色绒缎带背叛*
*Betrayed by the black velvet band*
*她的眼睛  闪耀着钻石般的光芒*
*Her eyes, they shone like diamonds*
*我以为她是这片土地的女王*
*I thought her the queen of the land*
*她的秀发  披在肩上*
*And her hair, it hung over her shoulder*
*用一根黑色绒缎带扎起*
*Tied up with a black velvet band.*
-你还好吧  -嗯  我没事
- You OK? - Yeah, I'm fine.
我觉得那边会有马车
I think there are some carriages over there
肯定会是空的  但是
that are going to be empty but...
天啊
Jesus.
弗莱迪
Freddie?
你回来了
You came back?
有人向我通风报信了
I got a tip-off.
弗莱迪  汤米会杀了你的
Freddie, Tommy will kill you.
就是汤米给我通风报信的
It was Tommy who tipped me off.
或许他还是有点人性的
Maybe he's got half a heart after all.
汤米给我送了一条信息
Tommy got a message to me.
上面写着"离开这里  带上她一起走"
It said "Get out of town and take her with you."
所以
So...
艾达·谢尔比
Ada Shelby...
你愿意嫁给我吗
will you marry me?
我愿意
Yes.
好了  快登上火车  赶紧离开这里
Right, get on that bloody train and get out of here.
-快点  你们两个  -弗莱迪  快来啊
- Come on, both of you. - Freddie, come on.
弗莱迪  卡迪夫那边很安全
Freddie, Cardiff's OK.
只要不是这儿  在哪儿都安全
Anywhere but here's OK.
我们哪儿都不去  艾达
We're not going anywhere, Ada!
我们要留在这里  在这儿结婚
We're going to stay here and we're going to marry here.
我不怕汤米·谢尔比
I'm not afraid of Tommy Shelby!
*让我看看你的微笑*
*Give me your smile*
*你眼里闪动的爱火*
*The love light in your eyes*
把牌洗一洗
Shuffle these cards...
去跟芬恩玩响指游戏去吧
Go and play snap with Finn.
你也想要威士忌吗
Did you want whiskey as well?
不  啤酒就好
No, just beer.
为什么不喝威士忌  汤米
Why no whiskey, Tommy?
你觉得待会儿会出乱子吗
Are you expecting trouble?
天啊  汤米  你何苦允许他们唱歌
Jesus Christ, Tommy, what the hell made you let them sing?
他们唱的就像是在勒死猫一样
They sound like they're strangling cats out there.
好了  二十底注  来吧
All right, 20 to play. Come on.
你为什么改变主意了  汤米
What did make you change your mind though, Tommy?
是啊  现在也该是时候了  汤米
Yeah, I mean, it's about time, Tommy.
干什么的时候
Time for what?
你该找个女人的时候
Time you took yourself a woman.
玩你的牌去吧
Just play the bloody hands.
你再继续这样下去  汤米
You stay the way you are, Tommy.
记住老爸曾经常说的话
Remember what Dad used to say-
"快换的女人  慢跑的马
"Fast women and slow horses...
毁你一生没商量"
"..Will ruin your life."
警察来了
Coppers.
不是
No.
*快来  乔瑟芬  来我的飞行器里*
*Come, Josephine, in my flying machine*
*她飞上天去*
*Up she goes*
*像鸟一样掌握着平衡*
*Balance yourself like a bird...*
我操
Holy shit.
是比利·肯波
It's Billy Kimber.
这里有个叫谢尔比的人吗
Is there any man here named Shelby?
我问  这里有个叫谢尔比的人吗
I said, is there any man here named Shelby?
哈里  给这些人上酒
Harry, get these men a drink.
其他人都回家吧
Everyone else, go home.
你  也回家
You, go home.
-但芬顿先生说  -我说让你回家去
- But Mr Fenton said... - I said go home.
我从没赞许过在酒吧里做工的女人
I've never approved of women in pubs
但长成这样的
but when they look like that...
你刚刚说要找叫谢尔比的人
You said you wanted men called Shelby.
我们这儿有三个
You've got three of them.
好吧  我本来从来没听说过你
Right, I'd never heard of you,
但后来确实听说了
then I did hear of you,
组成了什么剃刀党  我就心想  那又怎样
some little Didicoy razor gang. I thought to myself, so what?
但之后你们狠狠坑了我一把
But then you fuck me over
所以现在你们吸引了我全部的注意力
so now you have my undivided attention.
顺便问一句  我该跟谁谈  谁是老大
By the way, which one am I talking to? Who's the boss?
我是最年长的
Well, I'm the oldest.
显然嘛
Clearly.
你是在嘲笑我哥哥吗
Are you laughing at my brother?
好了  他是最年长的  你是最愚蠢的
Right, he's the oldest, you're the thickest.
我听说你们的老大叫汤米  我猜就是你了吧
I'm told the boss is called Tommy and I'm guessing that's you
因为你不停地上下打量我
cos you're looking me up and down
就像我是个妓女一样
like I'm a fucking tart.
我想知道你要怎么样
I want to know what you want.
坎普敦赛马场出现了可疑的赌马模式
There were suspicious betting patterns at Kempton Park.
事关一匹叫做摩纳根小子的马
A horse called Monaghan Boy.
它前两次大举获胜  第三次却倒数第一
He won by a length twice and then finished last
当时压在它身上的赌资有3000英镑
with 3,000 pounds bet on him.
我该跟谁谈才对
Which one am I talking to?
你们两个哪个才是老大
Which one of you is the boss?
我是肯波先生的顾问和会计师
I am Mr Kimber's advisor and accountant.
我才是老大  明白吗
And I'm the fucking boss, OK?
好了  没什么好谈判的了
Right, end of parley,
你们没经过我的允许操纵了比赛
you fixed a race without my permission.
你们这些吉普赛狗杂种  用诡计骗取了加里森街
You fucking Gypsy scum what live off the war pensions
那些可怜的寡妇们得到的战争抚恤金
of these poor old Garrison Lane widows!
那是你们才干的下贱的事
That's your level!
我是比利·肯波  我运营的是赛马生意
I am Billy Kimber, I run the races
你们竟敢操纵一场比赛
and you fixed one of them
我一定要让你们死无葬身之地
so I'm going to have you shot against a post.
肯波先生
Mr Kimber.
你看看
Look at it.
上面刻的是我的名字
That is my name on it.
是李氏家族的人干的
It's from the Lee family.
你也在和他们交战  对吧  肯波先生
You are also at war with the Lees, Mr Kimber, am I right?
李氏家族的人袭击了你的赌马生意
The Lees are attacking your bookies
抢走了你的钱
and taking your money.
你手下的人无法控制他们
Your men can't control them.
你需要帮助
You need help.
或许我们该听听谢尔比先生有什么话想说
Perhaps we should listen to what Mr Shelby has to say.
然后再做决定
Before we make our decisions.
好吧  李氏家族的人在集市上闲言碎语很多
Right, the Lees are doing a lot of talking at the fairs.
他们的亲族很多
They have a lot of kin.
他们说赛马生意是容易到手的肥肉
They're saying the racetracks are easy meat
因为警察在忙着应付罢工事件
because the police are busy with strikes.
现在  我们有了共同的联系
Now, we have connections.
我们知道他们的运作方式
We know how they operate.
你有大把的人手
You have muscle.
我们合力可以打垮他们
Together we can beat them.
但分而作战  就不一定了
Divided, maybe not.
肯波先生  或许我们该花点时间仔细考虑一下
Mr Kimber, perhaps we should take some time for reflection.
或许再安排第二次会面
Possibly make arrangements for a second meeting.
我很崇敬你  肯波先生
I admire you, Mr Kimber.
你白手起家  建立了合法的生意
You started with nothing and built a legitimate business.
如果能跟你合作真的很荣幸  肯波先生
It would be an honour to work with you, Mr Kimber.
没人可以跟我合作
Nobody works with me.
都只能在我手下工作
People work for me.
捡起来吧  吉普赛小子
Pick it up, pikey.
坐  坐下
Sit. Sit down.
那是给你修补天花板的钱
That's for your ceiling.
谢谢你  肯波先生
Thank you, Mr Kimber.
我们会去切尔滕纳姆的
We will be at Cheltenham.
我也会去的
As will I.
所以你是故意跟李氏家族那些人干架的
So you picked a fight with the Lees on purpose.
汤米  我们不能惹狗日的比利·肯波
Tommy, we can't mess with Billy fucking Kimber.
去把你的头发理得好看一点  老哥
Get yourself a decent haircut, man.
我们要去赛马场了
We're going to the races.